<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Stephen Lu</title>
 <link href="munk801.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="munk801.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2013-08-12T22:36:04-05:00</updated>
 <id>munk801.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Stephen Lu</name>
 </author>
 
 
 <entry>
   <title>A New Beginning</title>
   <link href="munk801.github.io/posts/new-beginning"/>
   <updated>2013-08-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>munk801.github.io/posts/new-beginning</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is definitely the start of something new and fun.  I have so many ideas and was once
told that only a fool wouldn&amp;rsquo;t write their ideas down and share them with the world.  So,
this is the start of that.  I am starting this off by just introducing myself.  My name
is Stephen Lu.  I am currently a Pipeline Tools Technical Director at Reel FX Animation
Studios.  I am currently located in Dallas and loving the journey I am on.  I am constantly
driving to learn more and share the knowledge I have found.  I have been always looking
at new opportunities and hope to share my journey with other people.  I also look to inspire
those wanting to be in the film/visual effects industry that are just starting out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I know is that it can be very daunting to try to get into this industry.  There
is so much to learn, and so many things for one person to partake.  I will tell you now
that though you may sometimes not feel sufficient enough to undergo something as big as
this industry is, you have to keep your head up and know that your passion and motivation
will be the driving force through this.  So with that, I will hope to bring any knowledge
I learn to help better this generation all around us.  Let the battle begin!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, follow and ping me on Twitter- I&amp;rsquo;m
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stephenmunklu&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>