<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Stephen Lu</title>
 <link href="http://munk801.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://munk801.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2013-12-25T19:34:43-06:00</updated>
 <id>http://munk801.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Stephen Lu</name>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Vacation as Motivation</title>
   <link href="http://munk801.github.io/posts/vacation-as-motivation"/>
   <updated>2013-12-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://munk801.github.io/posts/vacation-as-motivation</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So it is roughly a month away before I get a two week vacation to the beautiful country of Vietnam.
I have a lot of family there and it is always such a treat to be able to spend a few weeks without
worrying about life and responsibilities.  Though I have a vacation coming up soon,  this gives
me a new sense of motivation for vacations.  Some things that I realized is that I really need
to brush up on my vietnamese.  To give you an idea, I have about the language comprehension of a
12 year old when it comes to speaking vietnamese.  This gave me the drive to learn as much as I
can before the vacation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking about this, I had a realization about motivating myself before the vacation time.  I
thought that if I apply this to learning a language, I can use this with everything that I am
goaling towards right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, I am also looking to get more in shape before I go so I can appreciate my physical
self while I am on vacation and eat as much as I want without feeling guilty.  I feel like this
is also good motivation to getting in shape as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can this apply to my coding?  I can use this month to really take as much as I can working
on personal projects and learning new things so that I can have that sense of satisfaction
before I can give my mind the rest.  Think of it as that last strong push before resting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An update to learning Ruby and Rails.  Things are going quite decently, even though I am not
the biggest fan of rails structure of convention over configuration &amp;ldquo;The idea that if you follow
a certain convention, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to do all the configuration yourself&amp;rdquo;.  I prefer having
the control and knowledge of what I can do.  I hope to create some notes on some of the
things I have learned coming from a python side.  Maybe a &amp;ldquo;Learn Ruby from the Python Side&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, follow and ping me on Twitter- I&amp;rsquo;m
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stephenmunklu&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Use Ideas to Challenge Your Learning</title>
   <link href="http://munk801.github.io/posts/use-projects-to-challenge-learning"/>
   <updated>2013-10-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://munk801.github.io/posts/use-projects-to-challenge-learning</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So there has been something that I have recently been getting into the habit of doing.
I will be super motivated to want to do something and within an hour, write down ideas,
plan out what I will be doing and how I will be doing it.  I will research as much as
I can within that amount of time and really find all the determination I can to learn
what I need to learn.  This will include bookmarking a million websites I think will be
useful, finding all the books on the topic, and looking up all the tutorials I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem that I face, which seems to be something a lot of people face, is that we create
such a high benchmark for ourselves for this task we look to achieve, that we end up falling
flat on our faces after no longer than a few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After beating myself up countless times on making projects for myself and not keeping to
my promise, I wanted to find the reason that we are not keeping ourselves going.  I am going
to start with the learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that I have noticed a trend in is that a lot of projects has some learning
involved.  Whether this be learning a new programming language for your particular task,
a framework which is involved with your project, a customer base in which you want your project
to target, there is always some new type of learning that is involved with this.  Now, the question
comes to why can&amp;rsquo;t we follow through with the learning to accomplish this task?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find that we can&amp;rsquo;t learn these things because of the initial project we start off with.
Some of us are so ambitious to create the next big thing or to do something of such large scale,
that internally deters us away from ever reaching our goal.  If you were looking to pick up something
like running, you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t immediately goal yourself to olympic levels would you?  Or if you are looking
to pick up rock climbing, you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t goal yourself to the hardest climb you can find.  I mean, sure
that is a future goal that we often look to find, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t something that should immediately be
driving us to learn what it is we need to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to start with a very small project.  Something that would be both satisfying and give you
that feeling of accomplishment.  Let us remember that we are in the state of &amp;ldquo;learning&amp;rdquo; still.  This
is the time we can take to enjoy the information we are receiving and having this small project will
be the motivational factor that keeps us going.  As a runner, seeking to run a target set in a certain
amount of time.  As a rock climber, finding a decent route that you cannot initially do but can goal
towards.  As a developer, taking a small prjoect or even a small subset of your ambitious project
and using that to boost your learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, follow and ping me on Twitter- I&amp;rsquo;m
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stephenmunklu&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Create Small Goals to Improve</title>
   <link href="http://munk801.github.io/posts/create-small-goals"/>
   <updated>2013-09-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://munk801.github.io/posts/create-small-goals</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is on a little bit of a personal note as well but I thought that it would be worth sharing.
Right now is the beginning of the fall time and this is the time when people are beginning to go
back to school and start up class again.  Now, I am currently out of school and working so this
does not really affect me nearly as much as I am currently working but the timeline naturally
fits to create some fall goals for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you are in school or out of school, as a developer, it is a great idea to create term
goals for yourself to help you accomplish things you seek to complete.  This is also a very
important thing if you want to become a Technical Director, Artist, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that I have learned being out of school and being in the work force for a little
over a year, is that your &amp;ldquo;school&amp;rdquo; work doesn&amp;rsquo;t prove to the companies out there that you
are a competent worker and can fulfill yourself.  These are done through your personal
projects and most of the efforts that you perform outside of school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a technical director, the companies that I applied for were not asking me about my grades
and what I learned in school.  They asked about some of the projects that I have worked on
that involved communicating with a team and the roles that we played to create an effective
environment for accomplishing a task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, this isn&amp;rsquo;t to say that this can come from school as well.  When I interview with
Rhythm &amp;amp; Hues for an opportunity as a pipeline technical director, my projects from my
Scientific Visualization class really shined as much of it was python based and showed them
that I can create tools to visualize data.  I was lucky enough to find a class where the
professor gave us the freedom to create our own projects and own research to receive a
grade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I want to point out, is to not just do things for the grade.  The grade only lasts
for the semester and won&amp;rsquo;t take you much further.  The content, however, will take you much
further.  If you are in a computer science class learning python and algorithms, why not
take what you learn and create your own projects that visualize the algorithms?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In turn, take some time to create a fall goal list that does not pertain directly to school
work.  Look at your classes and try to look at how you can apply those into your personal
projects.  If you are taking a programming languages course, why not create a lexical
analyzer to analyze a toy language?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, follow and ping me on Twitter- I&amp;rsquo;m
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stephenmunklu&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Bad Changes Can Turn Into Good Changes</title>
   <link href="http://munk801.github.io/posts/bad-changes-can-turn-into-good-change"/>
   <updated>2013-09-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://munk801.github.io/posts/bad-changes-can-turn-into-good-change</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am currently flying back from a trip to Salt Lake City and decided to post something
more of a personal thought.  I have had some stressful times as of recently and it has
been something that has kept me more on my feet beyond anything.  It also has given me
a realization about our drives and motivations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We easily fall into a matter of &amp;ldquo;comfortablility&amp;rdquo; in which we are happy with what we
are given and therefore, lose that motivation to continue and pursue something bigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently in the process of losing a relationship and a friend for the time being.
Though I do not want to get too much into detail about this, I do want to elaborate more
on my mindset and how previous experience how shown that these sort of situations can
become a blessing in disguise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the process of a break up, it is very easy to fall into that mode of living where you
feel like your life does not suffice because you are unable to maintain that relationship.
What used to be habit and daily activities are gone and you must suddenly take all this
in and immediately habituate yourself to the siutation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people see these sort of situations as being very detrimental in our lives.  However,
I want to go out on a limb and say that this sort of situation can actually be a blessing
in disguise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I will go in and say that my mindset is very flustered,  I am constantly thinking, I
do get those very low images of myself from the situation.  However, something else has risen
from this event.  My motivation has been grown back into the place that I want it to be.  I
have become more organized than I have been in a while.  My thoughts have become more concentrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This recent trip has taught me a lot and given me a very clear idea of what I need to do.  My focus
on myself has grown.  Now, the question that you may be asking is how has a bad situation like this
giving you the ability to give yourself more focus.  The answer to that comes from trying to fill
your brain with these tasks rather than the sad thoughts that may come to you when you do not keep
your mind active.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without these thoughts to keep my mind busy and to keep myself active, my brain will immediately
fall into that category of reminiscing all the good times that you once had with your significant
other or even fall into the habits that you used to fall into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, I leave you with this.  You want to change the world.  You want to become something
better for yourself.  We all fall into bad situations and even bad days.  Take these tasks and pull
your mind away from the real world.  Go and work on your project.  Whether it be an art project, dance,
programming task, financial ventures, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, follow and ping me on Twitter- I&amp;rsquo;m
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stephenmunklu&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Writing Things Down</title>
   <link href="http://munk801.github.io/posts/13-writing-things-down"/>
   <updated>2013-08-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://munk801.github.io/posts/13-writing-things-down</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have noticed a trend with writing things down going in two pathes.  The first path is the path which you write everything down and try to keep track of everything you write.
The other is the exact counter-part which is not writing anything down in the mind that you find it hopeless since you will lose it anyways.  There are valid reasonings for
both of these sort of methodologies to writing things down.  You may want to write everything down so you can keep track of all your information and make sure you don&amp;rsquo;t
lose track of any of your thoughts.  One big drawback to this is that you can lose yourself in this mental library of items without some sort of organization system.
If you were to write down all your ideas and had no way of mentally mapping yourself back to this, why would you write things down?  Which brings forth the other end of
the spectrum which is not writing anything down because you know you will lose track of it anyways.  Though another big drawback to something like this is forgetfulness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have found that taking both aspects into one helps this process out quite a bit.  I like to call this moreso the &amp;ldquo;buddhist&amp;rdquo; mentality of writing things down.  This method
involves always having some sort of writing tool handy.  Whether this be a pencil, pen, chalk, dry erase marker, crayola, etc.  The idea is the write down all your thoughts,
so you have the information on &amp;ldquo;file&amp;rdquo;.  The next thing would be to store the information that you know you need to store.  Now, for the rest of the information.  Take your
time and really absorb that information.  Let the &amp;ldquo;phyical&amp;rdquo; nature of the thought be absorbed into your mind.  From there, that though is now with you and you no longer need
that physical copy.  Toss it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole idea behind this is that writing this material down becomes more a form of self memory and allows you to organize your mind and thoughts.  This is where some thing such
as a white board comes in handy because it was completely built on being erased.  Take advantage of the ability to write and the ability to write down all these great ideas.
Use it more to sift through everything rather than to try and remember all the details on the paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, follow and ping me on Twitter- I&amp;rsquo;m
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stephenmunklu&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>What is a TD?</title>
   <link href="http://munk801.github.io/posts/what-is-a-td"/>
   <updated>2013-08-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://munk801.github.io/posts/what-is-a-td</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I always have conversations with friends and strangers.  One of the questions that always seem to arise is &amp;ldquo;What is a Technial Director?&amp;rdquo;.
I am sure you may be asking yourself the same question and to be honest, there is a lot of generality when looking at the name Technical Director.
Now I am speaking not as a veteran in the industry but merely a student and recent TD which may help people better understand what a Technical Director
is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, you may hear this term and immediately put it up in the role of a &amp;ldquo;director&amp;rdquo;.  Though the status of a TD may not be quite up there in the
industry ladder, the idea is fairly similar.  Just as a director makes decisions and chooses the paths the film decides to take, a TD&amp;rsquo;s role involves
making decisions and choosing the path of the technical workflow.  Now, this role can vary to different specifications.  I will talk mainly about
the TD aspect in the pipeline development as I have most knowledge in this area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a friend and co-worker once said, a TD&amp;rsquo;s role is to make the lives of everyone else in the production easier.  Just as technology improves the
workflow of our lives, so must our roles as TDs improve the workflow of the studio.  Now a question that make come up is how do we improve the workflow?
There are many things that are involved to improving the workflow of the artist, the studio, and ourselves as TDs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will talk in my future posts about things that I have learend that I either wished I learned earlier or know will be useful in any case for any
aspiring TDs out there looking to fulfill their dream and create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, follow and ping me on Twitter- I&amp;rsquo;m
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stephenmunklu&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A New Beginning</title>
   <link href="http://munk801.github.io/posts/new-beginning"/>
   <updated>2013-08-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://munk801.github.io/posts/new-beginning</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is definitely the start of something new and fun.  I have so many ideas and was once
told that only a fool wouldn&amp;rsquo;t write their ideas down and share them with the world.  So,
this is the start of that.  I am starting this off by just introducing myself.  My name
is Stephen Lu.  I am currently a Pipeline Tools Technical Director at Reel FX Animation
Studios.  I am currently located in Dallas and loving the journey I am on.  I am constantly
driving to learn more and share the knowledge I have found.  I have been always looking
at new opportunities and hope to share my journey with other people.  I also look to inspire
those wanting to be in the film/visual effects industry that are just starting out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I know is that it can be very daunting to try to get into this industry.  There
is so much to learn, and so many things for one person to partake.  I will tell you now
that though you may sometimes not feel sufficient enough to undergo something as big as
this industry is, you have to keep your head up and know that your passion and motivation
will be the driving force through this.  So with that, I will hope to bring any knowledge
I learn to help better this generation all around us.  Let the battle begin!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, follow and ping me on Twitter- I&amp;rsquo;m
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stephenmunklu&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
