<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Stephen Lu</title>
 <link href="http://munk801.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://munk801.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2013-08-26T22:40:47-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://munk801.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Stephen Lu</name>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>What is a TD?</title>
   <link href="http://munk801.github.io/posts/what-is-a-td"/>
   <updated>2013-08-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://munk801.github.io/posts/what-is-a-td</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I always have conversations with friends and strangers.  One of the questions that always seem to arise is &amp;ldquo;What is a Technial Director?&amp;rdquo;.
I am sure you may be asking yourself the same question and to be honest, there is a lot of generality when looking at the name Technical Director.
Now I am speaking not as a veteran in the industry but merely a student and recent TD which may help people better understand what a Technical Director
is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, you may hear this term and immediately put it up in the role of a &amp;ldquo;director&amp;rdquo;.  Though the status of a TD may not be quite up there in the
industry ladder, the idea is fairly similar.  Just as a director makes decisions and chooses the paths the film decides to take, a TD&amp;rsquo;s role involves
making decisions and choosing the path of the technical workflow.  Now, this role can vary to different specifications.  I will talk mainly about
the TD aspect in the pipeline development as I have most knowledge in this area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a friend and co-worker once said, a TD&amp;rsquo;s role is to make the lives of everyone else in the production easier.  Just as technology improves the
workflow of our lives, so must our roles as TDs improve the workflow of the studio.  Now a question that make come up is how do we improve the workflow?
There are many things that are involved to improving the workflow of the artist, the studio, and ourselves as TDs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will talk in my future posts about things that I have learend that I either wished I learned earlier or know will be useful in any case for any
aspiring TDs out there looking to fulfill their dream and create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, follow and ping me on Twitter- I&amp;rsquo;m
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stephenmunklu&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A New Beginning</title>
   <link href="http://munk801.github.io/posts/new-beginning"/>
   <updated>2013-08-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://munk801.github.io/posts/new-beginning</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is definitely the start of something new and fun.  I have so many ideas and was once
told that only a fool wouldn&amp;rsquo;t write their ideas down and share them with the world.  So,
this is the start of that.  I am starting this off by just introducing myself.  My name
is Stephen Lu.  I am currently a Pipeline Tools Technical Director at Reel FX Animation
Studios.  I am currently located in Dallas and loving the journey I am on.  I am constantly
driving to learn more and share the knowledge I have found.  I have been always looking
at new opportunities and hope to share my journey with other people.  I also look to inspire
those wanting to be in the film/visual effects industry that are just starting out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I know is that it can be very daunting to try to get into this industry.  There
is so much to learn, and so many things for one person to partake.  I will tell you now
that though you may sometimes not feel sufficient enough to undergo something as big as
this industry is, you have to keep your head up and know that your passion and motivation
will be the driving force through this.  So with that, I will hope to bring any knowledge
I learn to help better this generation all around us.  Let the battle begin!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, follow and ping me on Twitter- I&amp;rsquo;m
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stephenmunklu&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
